matt@burythehammer.com http://www.burythehammer.com http://github.com/burythehammer

# Matt Long

I specialise in the creation and deployment of automated testing frameworks.

I have both the strong technical background required of a software developer, and a breadth of experience testing different platforms. This makes me a particularly talented individual to improve the quality of software products.

Not only that, I am a thought leader in my space, having presented at QCon - the largest development conference in the UK - the Community For Agile Testing, the London Hashicorp User Group, and I am booked to appear at muCon and Agile Cambridge.

Having worked as a consultant for many years, my experience is both broad and deep. I have worked for a variety of projects in many fields. I back it up with a strong academic profile, with physics and computer science degrees from two of the UK's best universities. I was also once a physics teacher, proving my communication abilities and emotional intelligence.

I have a strong belief in agile / devops practices, and most importantly, embedding testers within cross-functional teams. An automation first approach - to testing and infrastructure - is vital if teams are to deploy quickly and reliably. Because I have been working in such teams for years, I have gained great amounts of cross functional knowledge - with programmable infrastructure (e.g. Terraform, Ansible), with noSQL databases (e.g. Cassandra, Neo4J), with cloud infrastructure (e.g. AWS, Azure), and with serverless tech (Lambda).

I write testing blogs for opencredo.com, and I also maintain an irregular blog at burythehammer.com on testing and other interests. In my spare time, I maintain a machine learning foosball bot, written in Python.

#### Languages and frameworks

Ruby, Java 8, Javascript, Ruby, Golang, Python, Gherkin, VBScript

#### **Approaches**

BDD, TDD, Agile (both Scrum & Kanban), CI/CD, DevOps

#### Frameworks / Tools

Cucumber, Capybara, Selenium, Spring, RSpec, Mocha, Ginkgo, Gatling, QTP/UFT, HP ALM, Terraform, Ansible, AWS Lambda, Apex, Apache Spark, Jenkins

# Experience

# QA Consultant at OpenCredo, London (2015 – current)

OpenCredo is a open source consultancy, specialising in devops, big data, NoSQL databases and microservices.

As a QA consultant, I am primarily concerned with the construction, development, and maintenance of automated test frameworks. As well as the traditional roles associated with an SDET, I also advise clients on the entire development pipeline, improving quality across the board.

Being a consultant, I also have to use a variety of different languages and frameworks from month to month. I have built testing frameworks in Java, Ruby, Javascript, Golang, Python, Scala, in multiple different frameworks.

I also occasionally write about testing on our company tech blog, and have done several meetup and conference talks.

# Major projects:

## • Large consultancy cloud discovery

Consulting and advising the quality processes for a disorganised team delivering a cloud discovery platform, implemented in Lambda Serverless. Building integration and user acceptance tests in Javascript and Python.

#### Government cloud broker

Maintained and extended the Java Cucumber / Selenium test suite, and the Ruby infrastructure test suite of a cloud broker.

#### • Ethical Supply chain organisation

Maintained and extended the Java Cucumber / Selenium UI/API test suite of a large scale application developed with a microservice architecture deployed with Mesos.

## Consultant at Infuse Consulting, London (2012 – 2015)

Infuse is an automated testing consultancy that primarily works with HP's test suites. My role as a consultant was to build automated testing frameworks for our clients.

#### • Automated Test Engineer at ITV, London (Jan - Jul 2015)

Testing the complete rebuild of the ITV Player website. Developed Ruby Cucumber/RSpec acceptance tests, Gatling (Scala) performance tests, and exploratory testing of the site.

- Lead Tester for useMango, London (September 2013 December 2014)
- Lead the testing of our brand new test management and creation tool.
- The team lacked a clear testing strategy and made poor use of its existing tools. I brought structure to the testing by introducing a clear test strategy, training materials and resources, as well as introduced automated testing and CI practices.
- Proposed and developed a custom type of test that formed the bedrock of the deployment suite, by executing useMango's own tests against itself.
- Set up ALM to track the progress and deliver automatic and up-to-date reports to management. We were able to successfully deliver 3 major releases during my tenure,

none with any significant defects.

QA Engineer for a government project, Portsmouth (December 2012 - June 2013)

Developing automated scripts using HP's testing suite, primarily ALM and QTP. Took additional responsibility for test execution halfway through the project, from a senior colleague. This post required SC clearance.

## Science Teacher at Lampton School, Hounslow (June 2009 – September 2010)

Took the GTP, the Vocational equivalent of a PGCE course, with significantly more direct teaching experience and responsibility. This challenging but rewarding experience shaped me significantly, as it taught me how to manage people effectively and deal with stressful workloads. I taught science classes from ages 12-18 with a range of abilities and was responsible for all my own training.

# **Education and Qualifications**

University College London, London (2011 – 2012) MSc (Hons), Computer Science

Imperial College London, London (2005 – 2008) BSc (Hons), Physics

The King's School, London (2003 - 2008)

A-levels: Mathematics, Physics, English Language & Literature

AS Level: Further Mathematics

# Other Interests

Videogames, indiepop music, arthouse cinema, contemporary art, cycling, economics and current affairs.

References available on request.